<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jesse Atkinson</title>
    <link>https://jsatk.us/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jesse Atkinson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 15:53:15 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jsatk.us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Working With Thrift Unions in Scala</title>
      <link>https://jsatk.us/posts/working-with-thrift-unions-in-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 15:53:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsatk.us/posts/working-with-thrift-unions-in-scala/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been working a lot with Unions in Scala and have found it to be mildly confusing. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get tripped up so I wanted to write down a guide of sorts on how to work with them, particularly in Scala.
A brief primer First lets go over what we&amp;rsquo;re dealing with here when we&amp;rsquo;re dealing with an IDL in Scala. IDL stands for Interactive Data Language (IDL). The codebase I primarily work in in my day-to-day we write our IDLs in Thrift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whelp.  Let&#39;s try this again...</title>
      <link>https://jsatk.us/posts/new-website-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 23:22:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsatk.us/posts/new-website-launch/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been publishing my writing on the internet for approximately 23 years. I&amp;rsquo;d have never dared call it &amp;ldquo;publishing&amp;rdquo; or even &amp;ldquo;writing&amp;rdquo; in my earlier years. When I was 12 I created a website on Angelfire – which I think I chose only because it had a smaller ad-banner than Geocities – that was a complete rip-off of another cooler website I&amp;rsquo;d found detailing skateboard tricks. Despite not being able to ollie I decided this was going to be the focus of my first website and therefore my first &amp;ldquo;blog&amp;rdquo; (that portmanteau wasn&amp;rsquo;t in wide usage yet).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Et Cetera</title>
      <link>https://jsatk.us/et-cetera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 11:56:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsatk.us/et-cetera/</guid>
      <description>This page serves as a reference page of sorts. A combination of answers to FAQs &amp;amp; recommendations. A brain dump to house everything that I want to be able to point people to (or reference myself), but doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a sanctioned place on this site. It is focused on tech and software engineering.
 Tools  Software Hardware   Reference Library  Blogs    Tools Software  Vim - Forcing myself to properly learn Vim was one of the best decisions I ever made and has paid dividends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.plan</title>
      <link>https://jsatk.us/dotplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 11:30:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsatk.us/dotplan/</guid>
      <description>2020 .plan  Table of contents  January 2020  2020-01-02   March 2020  2020-03-27 2020-03-28 2020-03-29   May 2020  2020-05-04   June 2020  2020-06-08 2020-06-12   September 2020  09-06-2020 09-07-2020 09-09-2020 09-15-2020   October 2020  10-05-2020 10-24-2020    January 2020 2020-01-16 Wow. I hardly used this in 2019. Lets see if 2020&amp;rsquo;s different.
Been learning a ton of Scala.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jsatk.us/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 11:41:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsatk.us/about/</guid>
      <description>Personal  Hello, my name is Jesse Atkinson. I write code for a living. I currently work at Credit Karma. These days I spend most of my day writing Scala. For the past decade or so I&#39;ve worked as a full-stack web developer, but focused on the front-end. I&#39;ve worked in just about every popular JS framework. My LinkedIn is the best place to go for more career info or you can grab my résumé here .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Tiny Lessons from Functional Programming</title>
      <link>https://jsatk.us/posts/three-tiny-lessons-from-functional-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsatk.us/posts/three-tiny-lessons-from-functional-programming/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on the Earnest engineering blog here.
In the past two years or so the term &amp;ldquo;Functional Programming&amp;rdquo; (FP for short) has cropped up everywhere. You can&amp;rsquo;t get away from it. Especially in javascript. It feels like every JS developer but me was invited to a cool FP party and all of a sudden traditional object-oriented programming (OO for short) was for dinosaurs.
Also in the past two years, more thinkpieces than I care to link to have been written stating why or why not FP is a good thing for the javascript community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Validation Library in JS Using Propositional Calculus</title>
      <link>https://jsatk.us/posts/creating-a-validation-library-in-js-using-propositional-calculus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsatk.us/posts/creating-a-validation-library-in-js-using-propositional-calculus/</guid>
      <description>Published on the Earnest engineering blog here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Code: Part I - Alfred &#43; Dash</title>
      <link>https://jsatk.us/posts/how-i-code-alfred-and-dash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsatk.us/posts/how-i-code-alfred-and-dash/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in a series I plan on doing. Practical tips and lessons learned that I apply to my work or use daily.
As a developer, one of my favorite things is when I am pairing with someone and all of a sudden they do something magical. They convert JSON to CSV with a keystroke. They run only the staged files for git commit through the linter. They run the test suite from inside their editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Promise Rejections with Chai-As-Promised</title>
      <link>https://jsatk.us/posts/testing-promise-rejections-with-chai-as-promised/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsatk.us/posts/testing-promise-rejections-with-chai-as-promised/</guid>
      <description>I was recently working on a new npm module for work which is a promise-based API. Testing promises in javascript is very do-able, but also very tricky. You can test promises and their results in many various ways. Unfortunately the JS community seems still somewhat divided on how to properly test promises. The biggest problem I faced was that I needed to mock a third-party API. I avoid stubbing as much as humanly possible, but it is often necessary when testing third party code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Descent Into Madness with Vim, Tmux, &amp; Italics</title>
      <link>https://jsatk.us/posts/a-descent-into-madness-with-vim-tmux-and-italics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsatk.us/posts/a-descent-into-madness-with-vim-tmux-and-italics/</guid>
      <description>It all started out innocently enough. Eric Elliott retweeted this tweet by Max Stoiber. The tweet was meant to impart some great React knowledge upon me, however I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help, but be completely distracted by screen. What was that typeface? It&amp;rsquo;s absolutely beautiful. And his comments are rendered in italics, but this monospaced italics is different, it has&amp;hellip; cursive characters?! I must have this!
I quickly tweeted at him asking what font that was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aeropress Brew Methods</title>
      <link>https://jsatk.us/posts/aeropress-brew-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsatk.us/posts/aeropress-brew-methods/</guid>
      <description>Tonx Heart Roasters Stump Town Gridwriter  Tonx You will need:
 Tonx coffee (because it’s always fresh roasted) Near-boiling, filtered water Burr grinder Aeropress, with filters Spoon, or other agitating utensil   Measure out 14 grams of Tonx beans or one provided Aeropress scoop. Grind coffee a little finer than you would for a drip coffee maker or similar to coarseness of table salt. Place paper filter in filter holder and rinse — place handily off to side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermediate Git</title>
      <link>https://jsatk.us/posts/intermediate-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsatk.us/posts/intermediate-git/</guid>
      <description>What this post is  It is a tutorial of beginner to intermediate to maybe a light dusting of advanced git topics and practices. It is practical.  What this post is not  It is not philosophy or theory. (I will not be discussing the pros and cons of merge and rebase. Y&amp;rsquo;all can fight that battle elsewhere.) It is not super complex or overly archaic. It is not preachy (See first point).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Ten Hip-Hop Albums</title>
      <link>https://jsatk.us/posts/top-ten-hip-hop-albums/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsatk.us/posts/top-ten-hip-hop-albums/</guid>
      <description>Note: I&amp;rsquo;ve since lost when I originally wrote this so the publication date is an estimation by me from when I ported all my writings over to this website in 2020.
I love making lists like this. Don Woods did this so I had to too.
 &amp;ldquo;College Dropout&amp;rdquo; by Kanye West &amp;ldquo;Hell Hath No Fury&amp;rdquo; by Clipse &amp;ldquo;Late Registration&amp;rdquo; by Kanye West &amp;ldquo;Hello Nasty&amp;rdquo; by Beastie Boys &amp;ldquo;The Slim Shady LP&amp;rdquo; by Eminem &amp;ldquo;The Black Album&amp;rdquo; by Jay-Z &amp;ldquo;2001&amp;rdquo; by Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Text Editors</title>
      <link>https://jsatk.us/posts/on-text-editors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsatk.us/posts/on-text-editors/</guid>
      <description>Note: I&amp;rsquo;ve since lost when I originally wrote this so the publication date is an estimation by me from when I ported all my writings over to this website in 2020. Also this was originally broken up into six parts and published in six separate entries. I&amp;rsquo;ve since decided to combine them all into one here. Lastly, as of this writing, May 16, 2020, I probably disagree with some of this now and would tell you to just use Vim or Code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
